《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》前情回顾
NARRATOR: Previously on Battlestar Galactica...
卡布里卡上还有幸存者
STARBUCK: There are survivors on Caprica.
他们掀起了抵抗运动
A resistance movement.
我们一直在与赛昂人交战 不放过任何机会
ANDERS: We've been fighting the Cylons, hitting them where we can.
目前看来他们要留在这里了
Now it looks like they're here to stay.
他们要重建卡布里卡
They're rebuilding Caprica.
第一个莎伦是潜伏者
ADAMA: The first Sharon was a sleeper agent.
在她的程序启动之前 她并未意识到自己是赛昂人
Didn't realize she was a Cylon until her programming kicked in.
我是莎伦 但我是另一个莎伦
I'm Sharon, but I'm a different Sharon.
我是来帮忙的
And I'm here to help.
你是我的潜意识...
No, I've decided you are an expression
在清醒状态下…
of my subconscious mind playing itself out
自主行动的表现
during my waking states.
就是说我只存在于你的脑袋里么?
So, I'm only in your head?
我怀孕了  西洛  我们要有孩子了
BOOMER: I'm pregnant, Helo. We're gonna have a child.
莎伦会怀上我们的孩子?
Sharon is going to bear our child?
对她来说那本是遥不可及的荣誉
An honor for which she is hardly deserving,
但我不会对神的旨意提出质疑
but one doesn't question God's will.
赛昂人的转生?
The Cylons reincarnate.
很形象  不是么?
It makes sense, doesn't it?
他们的记忆全都下载到了一副新的躯体里
All our memories are downloaded to a brand-new body.
焕然一新
We're as good as new.
死亡变成了学习经验
Death becomes a learning experience.
等等  一定还有办法
Wait, there has to be another way out of here.
你一定有逃跑计划
I mean... I mean, you must have an escape plan.
你才不会自取灭亡的  是吧?
You're not about to be destroyed by your own bombs, are you, huh?
你怎么逃跑啊?
How are you leaving?
盖尤斯 我死不了
Gaius, I can't die.
当这副身体毁了以后 我的记忆
When this body's destroyed, my memory,
我的思想 就会被传送到一副新的躯体里
my consciousness will be transmitted to a new one.
我会在别处以一副同样的身体醒来
I'll just wake up somewhere else in an identical body.
你是说不止你一个?
You mean, there's more out there like you?
有12个型号  我是6号
There are 12 models. I'm number six.
我不想死
I don't want to die.
爬下
Get down.
你爱我么?
Do you love me?
我在… 我在…
Where? Where?
我刚才在一所房子里的
I was in a house.
可你已经不在房子里了
D'ANNA: But you're not in a house any longer.
你和我们在一起了
You're back with us.
你重生了
You've been reborn.
我死了
I died?
对 你刚才在一所房子里
That's right. You were in a house. It was destroyed.
房子被核弹的冲击波摧毁了
A nuclear blast.
但一切都过去了
But that is all over now.
你已经被下载到了一副新的躯体里
You have been downloaded into a new body.
盖尤斯
Gaius.
盖尤斯还在房子里
Gaius was in the house.
盖尤斯·波塔尔?
Gaius Baltar?
对  他还活着吗?
He's... Is he alive?
还活着吗?
Is he?
我不是真实的
BALTAR: I'm not really here.
除了你没有人能看到我
No one can see me but you.
别让他们知道
Don't let them know.
6号  如果波塔尔博士死了 你会难过么?
Six, would it trouble you if Dr. Baltar were dead?
如果他们知道了你对我的感情
If they know how you feel about me,
那就麻烦了
it'll be a problem.
如果他死了...
It would be unfortunate
那太不幸了
if he died.
他很有用
He was so helpful.
非常有用
Very helpful.
你的任务取得了重大成功
Your mission was a resounding success.
我们使殖民地防御系统彻底瘫痪了
We completely disabled the Colonial defenses.
袭击超出了我们最乐观的预测
The attack succeeded beyond our most optimistic projections,
这都拜你所赐
thanks to you.
你是机器  我不是
You're a machine. I'm not.
我知道很痛苦 呼吸  深呼吸
I know there's pain, but breathe. Ride through it.
没事的
You're going to be okay.
相信我
Trust me.
你在神的手中 我们都在陪着你
D'ANNA: You're in God's hands. We're all here with you.
好了
D'ANNA: That's it.
会过去的  相信我
D'ANNA: This will pass. Trust me.
一切都会好的
Everything's gonna be all right.
欢迎回家  妹妹
NO. 6: Welcome home, little sister.
大家都在这儿
We're here.
我们会照顾你的
We're going to take care of you.
我们为你感到骄傲  莎伦
DORAL: We're proud of you, Sharon.
我们爱你
And we love you.
不!
No!
它象征着重生
NO. 6: I was thinking it symbolized rebirth.
一个新的开始
A new beginning.
这是追悼仪式
BALTAR: It's a memorial.
你知道在那次袭击中 有多少人死在了这个公园里?
Do you know how many people died in this park during the attack?
单就在这个公园里死了多少?
How many people in this park alone?
这里会很美的  是吧?
It's gonna be lovely, isn't it?
这个公园…
This park.
一个舒展身心 整理思绪的地方
You know, a place to relax, collect your thoughts.
你还好么?
How you doing?
有点僵硬
I'm a little stiff.
还是对这身体不习惯
I'm still trying to get used to this body.
我明知道身体是一样的
I mean, I know it's identical,
可是即使经历了这么多次 还是觉得不自在
but even after all this time, I still feel awkward.
我也是笨手笨脚 常把东西打翻
I was a klutz, too. I used to knock things over.
总是嗑嗑绊绊
I was forever tripping over things and...
克服一下吧
You know what, you get over it.
这是一个净化自己的好机会
And you know what, this is a great chance to cleanse.
一副新身体 一个新生活
You've got a new body, a new life.
长久以来养成的焦虑
And anything that you've built up, like anxieties
懊悔  内疚...
or remorse or guilt,
你都可以抛到九霄云外了
just let it wash away.
真不知道该怎么感激你才好
I can't tell you how thankful I am.
你一直都在帮助我
You've been a really big help to me.
不  该说谢谢的是我
No, it's me who's thankful.
我们都该感谢你 你是勇士
We all are. You are a war hero.
如果没有你 我们不会取得胜利
We could not have won without you.
打扰了
Excuse me.
我只想说你来到了卡布里卡 是我们的荣幸
I just wanted to say, it's an honor to have you here on Caprica with us.
你所做的一切...
What you did...
令我们身心鼓舞
Well, that's inspiring.
谢谢
Thank you.
感觉怎么样了?
Hey. How you doing?
好冷
I'm freezing.
我的脚没知觉了
I can't feel my legs.
是硬膜外腔麻醉的关系
That's the epidural.
出了什么事?
What happened?
你刚才昏过去了 又开始流血了
You passed out and started bleeding again,
一切都会好的
but everything's gonna be all right.
可得了吧
Like hell it is.
你们真够可以的
I find it absolutely amazing.
你们费尽心机…
You people went to all the trouble
想看起来和人类一样 但却没升级生殖系统
to appear human and didn't upgrade the plumbing.
你的胎盘脱落了
You have a detached placenta.
现在就得把婴儿生下来 否则你们两个都有危险
Baby has to come out now, or we could lose you both.
先生  请出去一下
Okay, sir, I'm gonna have to ask you to step back, please.
她心动过速 血压在下降
She's tachycardic and her blood pressure's dropping.
又内出血了
Yeah, she's hemorrhaging again.
要立即开刀
We're gonna have to make the cut, now.
莎伦  能听见我说话么?
HELO: Sharon, can you hear me?
西洛
BOOMER: Helo.
还真是不习惯
I still can't get used to this.
你现在可是赛昂人的英雄了
Well, you're a hero of the Cylon now.
大明星了
You're our first celebrity.
不  我只是一个6号而已
No, I'm just another Six.
你太谦虚了 我只是一个3号
You're too modest. I'm just another Three,
那里还有5号和8号
and they're Fives and, oh, Eights.
但大家可都称呼你"卡布里卡6号"
But you? Everyone calls you Caprica Six,
好象这个星球上 只有你一个6号一样
like you're the only Six on the planet.
你所完成的任务是难点
And what you did was incredibly difficult.
为了获取
To seduce a man
人类的机密情报
so emotionally and physically, so that he grants you access
而去全身心地引诱一个男人
to all the most closely guarded secrets of his people.
这样的任务可是十分棘手
I mean, that mission could be profoundly disturbing.
棘手?
Disturbing?
是指和我上床 还是杀害几十亿的人?
She mean sleeping with me or killing billions of people?
因为我觉得你挺乐意和我上床的
Because I rather thought you enjoyed sleeping with me.
有些时侯是挺难的
It was difficult at times.
这里没人有你这样的经历
See, nobody here can possibly understand what you've been through,
所以我们才需要你的帮助
which is why we need your help.
还有一个赛昂人在下载之后 在重组方面…
There's another Cylon who's been having trouble reintegrating
遇到了一些问题
after a download.
事实上是另一个英雄
Another hero, actually.
一个8号 她仍坚持说自己是莎伦
An Eight still insists on calling herself Sharon.
你认为我可以帮上忙?
And you thought I could help?
我...
I'm still having...
我还有自己的问题没解决
I'm having problems of my own.
小卡  你不懂 她真的需要你的帮助
Caprica, you don't understand. She really needs your help.
如果我们不快些说服她 她就会被雪藏起来
If we don't turn her around soon, there's talk of boxing her.
把她的记忆存储起来? 不是真的吧?
Putting her memories in cold storage? You can't be serious!
这倒是处理 情感问题的有趣办法
Well, that's a charming way to deal with emotional problems.
可以说也是不人道的
One might almost call it inhuman.
对了  你们本来就不是人
Oh, that's right, you are.
这也将是下下策 但她的情况在恶化
All right, look, it is a last resort. But she's been regressing.
拜托了
Please.
她就住在上面那个公寓里
She's living up there in that apartment.
从她以为自己是人类的时候 就住在那里了
It's the one she had when she thought she was human.
守卫稀少 两名赛昂武士在前门外巡逻
Security's minimal. Two Centurions patrol out front.
第3名"子弹头"把守四周
The third bullet-head walks the perimeter.
四处巡逻的那个"子弹头"行踪不定
The bullet-head walking perimeter makes random changes to his patrol.
要过它那关可不容易
Be tough to get past him.
那咱们就从它下面过去
All right, so we go under them.
雨水沟直通到咖啡厅下面的停车场
The storm drain leads directly to the garage underneath the cafe.
那里面会有几十个"整容人"(人形赛昂人)
There'll be dozens of skin jobs inside.
她没气了
HELO: She's not breathing!
放到呼吸机里    马上
COTTLE: Suction it. ISHAY: Right away, doctor.
怎么回事? 要把她带哪去?
What's going on? Where are you taking her?
她的肺部还没有发育完全 需要氧气的支持
Her lungs aren't fully developed. She needs oxygen support.
那她还活着  是吧?
But she's alive, right? Right?
这就是答案 快出去吧
There's your answer. Now, you get the hell out of here.
我们要把母亲的血止住 不然她就危险了
We've got to stop the mother bleeding, or she's not going to make it.
你是来赶我出去的?
You here to kick me out?
不是
No.
那是来纠正我的问题的?
If you're here to help me with my adjustment problems,
省省吧
I can save you some time.
这是我的家
This is home.
我不会走
I'm not leaving.
我在卡布里卡住了两年 我知道自己是什么人
I lived on Caprica for two years. I knew what I was.
我装作是人类 这我知道
Pretended to be human, but I knew.
如果你对自己一清二楚 却还住在这里  你知道你成什么了么?
If you knew what you were and you lived on Caprica, you know what that makes you?
一个大骗子
A really good liar.
从大象入手
Start with the elephants.
好漂亮
These are beautiful.
伊萨卡造的?
Ithacan?
手工雕绘的
Hand carved.
我离家去舰队学院那天 我母亲送给我的
My mother gave them to me the day I left for the Fleet Academy.
是她么?
Is this her?
算是吧
Supposed to be.
反正都不是真的
Of course, none of it's real.
全都是为了我的任务而编造的
All fabricated for my mission.
都是谎言
It's all a lie.
追寻神的足迹 永远都不是一帆风顺的
Following God's path is never easy.
别把这事扯到宗教上面 你想什么呐?
Oh, don't go religious with this one. What are you thinking?
你以为我在乎你的神是谁吗?
Do you think I care about your God?
神是爱你的
Look, God loves you.
这才是爱
This is love.
这些人才是爱我的 我爱他们
These people love me. I love them.
我没有因为要害人 而去假装些什么
I didn't pretend to feel something so I could screw people over.
我爱他们 但却背叛了他们
I loved them. And then I betrayed them.
我向我敬爱的人开了枪
I shot a man I love.
又把另一个人的生活弄得一团糟  这一切都为了什么?!
Frakked over another man, ruined his life. And why?
因为我是一部说谎的机器!
Because I'm a lying machine!
我他妈是一个赛昂人!
I'm a frakking Cylon!
对不起 我不是故意的…
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to...
我这里有胶条
I've got bandages in the head.
干得漂亮 时间掐得恰倒好处
Nicely done. You timed it perfectly.
玻璃击中墙壁的一刹那
BALTAR: Scratch your face with the side of your fingernail
用自己的指甲划破了脸
the moment the glass hits the wall.
从没看过一个赛昂人会害怕 特别是6号
Never saw a Cylon show fear before, especially the Sixes.
他们总是无所畏惧
They're usually so hardcore.
装作胆小如鼠  感情脆弱 演技确实不错
Feign fear and emotional vulnerability. You're very good, you know.
可我更厉害 我来帮你吧
But I'm better. Let me help you.
"我与众不同"
I'm different.
我与众不同
"我更像你"
I'm more like you.
我曾在这里遇到过一个人 一个男人
I had someone I met here. A man.
我爱他 以为他最后会爱上我
I loved him and I think he could've loved me eventually.
半根烟有两三分钟的时间 够我们离开这里了
Half a cigarette should give us two or three minutes to get the frak out of there
如果时间久了 他们可能会在爆炸前发现引爆器
Any longer and we risk them finding the charges before they go off.
是两分钟 还是三分钟
Is it two minutes or three?
等会就知道了
About to find out.
这次冒险行动 只能干掉几个"整容人"
This is a risky operation just to nail a couple of dozen skin jobs.
他们是杀不死的
You know, we can't kill them.
他们还会下载到一副新的躯体里
They'll just download into a new body, and...
这又有什么用?
I mean, what's the point?
那个和星芭儿在一起的…
That skin job with Starbuck,
叫莎伦的人
Sharon, they called her,
她说当他们下载以后 他们会记住所有发生过的事
she said that when they download, they remember everything,
从头至尾
right up until the end.
"整容人"会记得被炸成四分五裂的样子
These skin jobs are gonna remember being blown into tiny little pieces.
够狠
That's gotta hurt.
恩 希望让他们痛不欲生
Yeah. I hope it hurts a lot.
因为迟早会让他们认识到 没有安身之地了
Because sooner or later the message sinks in. There is no safe place,
咖啡厅也不安全 所以如果他们不想再受罪了
not even a cafe. So if you want to quit living through hell
不想死了一次又一次 那就从咱们的星球上滚出去
and dying over and over again, then get the frak off our planet.
3分11秒
Three minutes, 10 seconds.
砰
Boom.
这座房子在湖边的断崖上
NO. 6: His house was on a bluff over a lake.
我一直喜欢这景色  阳光照在水面上
I always loved the view. The sunlight on the water.
那是全宇宙中  我最喜欢的地点
It's my favorite spot in the universe.
恩  美极了
Yes, magical.
可惜你把它炸平了
Too bad you nuked it.
在我的下载完成后  我又回到了他那房子的废墟前
After I downloaded, I went back to the ruins of his house.
为什么?
Why?
和你一样  我想找些和他有关的东西
Like you, I was looking for some sort of connection to him.
找到了一些他的物品  舍不得扔掉
Found a few of his things, even held on to them for a while,
但是我意识到它们在阻止 我接受新生活
but I realized they were keeping me from truly embracing my new life.
那你把那些东西怎么处理了?
BOOMER: So, what did you do with them?
烧了
I burned them.
但我感到一身轻松
But I felt liberated.
好一个动人的故事  不是么?
Yeah, it's a beautiful story, isn't it?
可惜全是一派胡言
A shame it's all a pack of lies.
那你爱的这个人是谁?
So, who was he? This man you loved?
可能你听说过他
Maybe you've heard of him.
盖尤斯·波塔尔
Gaius Baltar.
波塔尔博士?
Doctor Baltar?
恩
Yeah.
是他允许你进入了殖民地防御网
He gave you access to the Colonial defense grid?
是他背叛了我们?
He was the one who betrayed us?
"我们"   我喜欢
"Us. " Oh, I love it.
这家伙把她自己当成人类了
This one thinks she's more human than Cylon.
和我认识的一个人一样
Just like someone else I know.
他还是在为赛昂人效力么?
Does he still work for the Cylons?
什么?
What?
在卡拉狄加上?
On Galactica?
他...
He's...
他还活着?
He's alive?
他是殖民地的副总统
He's the Vice President of the Colonies.
你不知道?
You didn't know that?
如果她的孩子真活了下来 问题是我们该如何处置它?
If the baby does survive, the question is, what do we do with it?
处置?
Do?
你什么意思?
What are you suggesting?
要把它扔出过渡舱吗?
That we throw it out of an airlock?
我没什么意思  波塔尔先生
I don't make suggestions, Mr. Baltar.
如果我真要那么做  我会说一声的
If I want to toss a baby out an airlock, I'd say so.
不是要把孩子扼杀在摇篮中就好
Well, it's really gratifying to know that infanticide is not on the table.
是不是还非要我说出来  这可不是孩子
Do I have to point out that this is not a baby?
是一部机器
It's a machine.
不  是半人半机器
No, it's half machine, half human.
我建议各位  弄清楚那一半是什么
I suggest we all keep that half in mind.
赛昂人费尽周折创造了这个东西
The Cylons went through a great deal of trouble to create this thing.
不用说 如果对他们有好处  就是对我们有坏处
It should go without saying that if it's good for them, it's gonna be bad for us.
我完全同意
I completely agree.
显然我们不能交给莎伦来抚养
And I take it as a given, we can't turn it over to Sharon to raise.
那样会再生祸患
That would be disastrous.
还要考虑一个因素
ADAMA: There's still another factor to consider here.
这支舰队里有赛昂人
There are Cylons aboard this fleet.
如果他们得知这东西已经降生了
If they find out this thing's been born,
他们会借此大造舆论
they're gonna make a play for it.
看清局势了吧  盖尤斯
You can see where this is headed, Gaius.
我们要把孩子夺回来
We're gonna have to take our child.
你好  赫拉
BOOMER: Hello, Hera.
她手抓的好紧哦
She's got quite a grip on her.
你不喜欢在那里  是吧  赫拉?
You don't like it in there, do you, Hera?
你的肺部没发育好不能出来
You gotta stay until your lungs get stronger.
她是我们的小女孩
BOOMER: Oh, she's our little girl.
我们创造了她
We made her.
差点就让我信奉赛昂人的神了
Almost makes you want to believe in the Cylon God.
差点儿
Almost.
我好爱你
I love you so completely.
安全了
It's clear.
拿着这个
Here, take these.
走
Let's move!
给
Here you go.
你说他们为什么不告诉你?
Why do you think they kept it from you?
问错了
Is the wrong question.
应该问为什么她明知你会告诉我真相
The right question is, why did she get me to work with you,
还让我来劝导你?
knowing that you'd tell me the truth?
她知道我对盖尤斯有感情
She knew I had feelings for Gaius.
知道我对他念念不忘
Knew that I had trouble letting go of him.
她一定知道这样会激起你的感情
She must've known it would trigger those feelings,
还有记忆
and those memories.
她在耍你 你没看出来吗?
She's frakking with you, can't you see that?
但为了什么?
But why?
再明显不过了
Oh, it's so perfectly obvious.
对于一个拥有自我意识的 自主生命形态来说
You know, for self-aware cybernetic life forms,
有时会异常迟钝
sometimes you can be unbearably obtuse.
拜托    小心
Oh, for God's sake! BALTAR: Careful.
一切还好吧?
Everything okay?
挺好的
Fine.
在和莎伦聊天
Just talking with Sharon here.
是么? 聊什么?
Yeah, what about?
她让我搬走
She asked me to move out.
这事我们都催她几周了
Ah, you know what? Which is what we've been asking her for weeks.
我倒希望她和你聊完之后
I was kind of hoping that you'd see the light
你的脑筋会转转
after talking to our friend here.
可惜啊  她在撒谎
She is lying, unfortunately.
她可不希望莎伦过上好日子
She has no wish to see Sharon cured.
他们要动手啦
They're just gonna do it.
要雪藏她了
They're going to box her.
上面咖啡厅里有多少个赛昂人?
ANDERS: How many Cylons up in the cafe?
客满  至少40个
Full house. At least 40.
3分10秒
Three minutes, 10 seconds.
我们刚有所突破
We've just made a breakthrough.
她同意搬出来了
She's agreed to move out of her apartment.
是吧  莎伦?
Didn't you, Sharon?
恩
Yeah.
我要搬出去住
I'm moving out of the apartment.
什么时候搬?
When?
随时都可以
Whenever.
那现在就搬吧
What about now?
我来帮忙 正好就在楼上
I'll help. The apartments are right upstairs.
那好
Sure.
我去...我去拿些东西
Let me... Let me just get some things.
干得好  6号 一定费了不少唇舌吧?
Good work, Six. Must have been some chat, huh?
恩  我们聊了很多
Yes. We had a lot to talk about.
她就在你后面
She's right behind you.
知道
I know.
无须争论
This is not a debate.
这孩子不会交给赛昂人来抚养
This child will not be raised by the Cylon,
我不会冒险让赛昂人接近它  这我已经决定了
and I cannot risk Cylon agents getting their hands on it. I've made my decision.
我需要你的帮助  医生
What I need from you, Doctor, is your help.
好吧  虽说我不喜欢 但还是按你说的办吧
Fine. I don't like it, but have it your way.
现在就办
I need it immediately.
我们得找到合适人选
We'll have to find somebody suitable.
然后制订出一份名单
I have to work up a list of names.
这当中每个人都可以 都是匿名的  都可以信赖
Each of them is capable, each of them is anonymous, and each can be trusted.
都考虑周到了  是吧?
Thought of everything, haven't you?
但愿如此
I hope so.
没事吧  莎伦?
Are you all right, Sharon?
出了什么事?
What happened?
发生了爆炸
Explosion.
楼塌了压到了我们
Building came down on us.
看来是消防梯救了我们
Looks like the stairwell saved us.
6号在哪儿?
Where's Six?
她的身体死掉了
Her body's dead.
不  还没死
No, not yet.
帮我一下
Help me out here.
她还不如被炸死
Would've been better if the explosion had killed her.
出去之后才能帮她止痛
There's nothing we can do about the pain until we get out of here.
6号  我可以拿个横梁
Hey, Six, I can get a crossbeam
让你免受些罪
and put you out of your misery.
我不会再自杀了
I'm not gonna give up on life again.
随你吧
It's your choice.
我们这是在哪儿啊?
D'ANNA: Where the heck are we, anyway?
一定是停车场里
Must be in the garage.
北侧出口应该在那边
The north entrance might be that way.
我要开始挖了
Then I'm gonna start digging.
挺住
Hang in there.
没事的
BOOMER: You're gonna be okay.
一个幸存者?
Another survivor.
恩
Yeah.
挺住  兄弟
Hang on, buddy.
我们把你弄出来
We'll get you out.
新鲜空气从那下面来的
Fresh air coming from down there.
多谢  我以为自己死定了
Thanks. I thought I was a goner.
去他妈的人类 可能就是他一手造成的
Frakking human. You know, he probably set that explosion.
抵抗军干的?   为什么?
What, from the Resistance? Why?
咖啡厅并没有军事价值
No military value to the cafe.
但人类不像我们一样重视生命
Humans don't respect life the way we do.
不
No!
我不会让你杀了他
I won't let you kill him.
她说得对
She's right.
别杀他
Don't kill him.
为什么?
Why not?
嗯
Hmm.
为什么不结果了他?
Why not kill him?
你都已经杀了数十亿人了
You've already killed billions of people.
你真以为再多一个人 会加重你…
Do you honestly believe one more body's gonna weigh any heavier
良心的谴责么?
on your conscience?
你是没有良心的
Which is something that you don't have.
是吧?
Do you?
我们应该审问他
We should interrogate him.
找出他的同党
Find his accomplices.
好
Okay.
你可以放手了  莎伦
You can let go now, Sharon.
这是什么?
What's this?
像是殖民舰队的身份牌
BOOMER: Looks like Colonial Fleet ID.
卡拉·瑟瑞丝
"Thrace, Kara. "
星芭儿?
Starbuck?
她几星期前来过卡布里卡
She was on Caprica a couple of weeks ago.
另一个莎伦帮她逃跑了
She escaped with the help of another Sharon.
这是她给他的 他对她来说很重要
If she gave him this, he meant something to her.
好甜蜜
Well, ain't it sweet?
它就在你的手中
BALTAR: You have it in your hand.
那是一个人对另一个人爱的实证
Hard, physical proof of one person's love for another.
但愿你对我们的感情 也有这样深深的感受
If only you felt this deeply about us.
我曾有过这种感受
I did.
现在也有
I do.
我爱你  盖尤斯
I love you, Gaius.
有确凿的证据么?
Where's the tangible proof?
我不明白 她一直很好的
HELO: I don't understand. She was doing so well.
不  不是
COTTLE: Oh, no, she wasn't.
我本想告诉你的
I tried to tell you that.
她的肺部没有发育完全
Her lungs were never fully developed.
最终导致了呼吸窘迫症
She finally went into respiratory distress.
我们没能及时进行插管治疗 没能抢救过来
We couldn't get her intubated in time and we lost her.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我该一直在这里的
I should have been here.
莎伦 你应该多休息
HELO: Sharon, you need sleep, okay?
你失血太多了
You've lost a lot of blood.
是你杀了她
You murdered her.
莎伦  来吧
Sharon, come on.
谁下的命令?
Who ordered it?
是阿达玛  还是总统?  是谁?
Adama? The President? Who?
我是不会加害患者的
I don't kill patients.
我们尽了全力
We did the best we could.
可她还是死了
But she's dead.
就是这样
And that's all there is to it.
几小时内 我就会把骨灰给你们
I should be able to release the ashes to you in a few hours.
杀人犯
Murderer.
莎伦    去死!
HELO: Sharon! Sharon. Die!
你们都是杀人犯!
BOOMER: You're all murderers!
退后    你们都是杀人犯!
MAN: Stay back! You're all murderers!
把她带出去
Get her out of here!
放松 放松
Easy! Easy! Easy!
你让他们杀死了我们的孩子
You let them murder our child.
很抱歉
I am so sorry.
我尽全力了
I tried. I tried my best.
神的旨意是我们的孩子应该活下来
God's will was that our child should survive.
他的旨意是她会带领下一代神的子女
His will was that she would lead the next generation of God's children.
他的旨意是你应该保护她
His will was that you would protect her.
对
Yes.
你已经犯下了弥天大罪
Listen, you have committed a monstrous and unforgivable sin.
从现在开始 你和你那劣质的种族都将会遭天谴
And now you and your entire wretched race are gonna suffer God's vengeance.
她好美哦
She's so beautiful.
不知道该怎么感谢您
I don't know how to thank you.
当我失去了孩子的时候  都不知道该怎么活了
When I lost my baby, I didn't know how I could go on.
值得庆幸的是你和这小女孩挺投缘的
Well, I'm glad things worked out for you and this little girl.
不敢相信能有人会舍弃这个小天使
I can't believe somebody would give up this little angel.
玛雅  你也知道  这次收养事宜需要绝对保密
You understand, Maya, that this adoption requires absolute secrecy.
她的母亲是帕伽索斯上的军官
The mother is a Pegasus officer and must remain anonymous
因政治和宗教上的原因必须匿名
for political and religious reasons.
我保证
You have my word.
玛雅 我可以时不时地去看看她么?
Maya, you won't mind if I drop in occasionally?
当然可以
Oh, of course not.
好
Good.
去吧
Go.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我知道你一定很难受
I know how awful this was for you,
但相信我 这事关重大
but trust me, it was imperative.
只要赛昂人知道这孩子已经不在了
As far as the Cylons know, this child no longer exists.
就是大好事
That is a good, good thing.
在找这东西么?
Is this what you're looking for?
拿去吧
You can have it.
给
Here.
你在干吗?
What're you doing?
帮他达成目的
Just making it easy for him to get what he wants.
来吧  我给你开个头了
Come on. I'll give you a head start.
我这样挺好
I'm fine where I am.
他们来救我们了 来抓你了
Hey, they're coming for us and you.
他们会对你很感兴趣
They'll be very interested in you.
别烦他了
Leave him alone.
莎伦
Sharon,
你是赛昂人的英雄
you're a hero of the Cylon.
你现在只不过是一部以为自己是人类的破烂机器
Now you're just a broken machine who thinks she's a human.
你不是人类  莎伦
But you're not a human, Sharon,
永远不会是人类
and you never will be.
至少我不是杀人犯
Yeah, well, at least I'm not a murderer.
我有良心
I have a conscience.
并且明辨是非
And I know the difference between right and wrong.
你就是一个杀人犯
A murderer is exactly what you are.
生命短暂 来世的路还很长
Life is short, but the next one's not.
放逐你的心  留住你的魂
Let your heart adrift and your soul will get caught.
我爱你  盖尤斯
I love you, Gaius.
我的心和魂都是你的
My heart and soul are yours.
快进来了
They're nearly here.
知道他们为什么让你去劝说莎伦么?
You know why they wanted you to work with Sharon?
因为这样你就会疯掉
So you'd lose your mind.
他们就会雪藏你
They're gonna box you, darling.
像对待莎伦一样去雪藏你
Just like they're gonna box Sharon.
我们是危险人物
We're dangerous.
什么?
What?
莎伦和我
Sharon and I.
我们是生活在以团结为文明的世界中的名人
We're celebrities in a culture based on unity.
不
No.
我们有号召力 比她更有号召力 比别人都有号召力
Our voices count. More than hers. More than others'.
我们俩是赛昂人的英雄  不是么?
We're two heroes of the Cylon, right?
两个对战争持有不同观点的人
Two heroes with different perspectives on the war.
以我们对两个人类的爱为基础的观点
Perspectives based on our love of two human beings.
这就是她让我劝导你的原因
That's why she wanted me to work with you,
这样你就会告诉我盖尤斯还活着
so that you'd tell me that Gaius was still alive.
她想让我疯掉
And she wanted me to lose my mind.
你们早已被你们的经历所腐蚀了
No, you're corrupted by your experiences.
你们是废物
D'ANNA: You're a waste.
相信那些谎话
Believe the lies,
别去理会真相 听我的话 我会证明给你看的
ignore the truth. Listen to me, I will show you the proof.
实话实说
Speak from your heart.
说出你认为正确的事
Say the things that you know to be true.
嫉妒
Genocide,
谋杀  报复 都被神视为罪过
murder, vengeance, they're all sins in the eyes of God.
你我都知道这些
That's what you and I know.
他们却听不进去
That's what they don't wanna hear.
因为那样 他们就会反省自己
Because then they'd have to rethink what they're doing.
他们就会思考 屠杀人类也许是错误的
They'd have to consider that maybe the slaughter of mankind was a mistake!
神是爱我的
God loves me.
回见
We'll see you again soon!
这里
Here.
看来他们快进来了
Looks like they're almost here.
趁还有机会快走吧
You should get out of here while you can.
顺着新鲜空气进来的地方 可能就会出去
The fresh air coming in might lead you out.
你们是在逢场作戏么?
Is this some kind of trick?
如果想留下来受折磨也行
You can stay and be tortured if you want.
你自己决定
Your call.
你们是谁?  你们是什么人?
Who are you? What kind of people are you?
不知道
I don't know.
等下
BOOMER: Hey, wait.
再过多久她就会下载完毕  然后告发我们?
How long till she downloads and tells them what happened?
咖啡厅里曾有很多人
We had a lot of people in the cafe.
至少有36小时才能轮到她
At least 36 hours till they get to her.
时间够了
Long enough.
够干什么?
Long enough for what?
做好事
To change things for the better.
什么意思?
What are you talking about?
我这一生还从没像现在一样…
I have never loved anyone more in my life
如此爱你
than I love you now.
我们的人需要一个新的开始
Our people need a new beginning.
一种在神的眷顾之下的新的生活方式
A new way to live in God's love.
没有仇恨
Without hate.
没有谎言
Without all the lies.
他们只需要有人能引领他们
All they need is for someone to show them the way.
像是两个赛昂人的英雄
Someone like two heroes of the Cylons.
我们誓死在一起
I'm with you.
找到她们了
DORAL: We found them!
她们还活着
They're alive!
是的  还活着
Yes, we are!
我们还活着
We're alive.